# **Agusti Bau**

■agustibau@gmail.com □+34699540050 ■ in/agustibau • www.agustibau.com

## **SUMMARY**

I'm a software engineer with 3 years of experience. I've spent most of my time developing backend systems with java. Nonetheless, I'm always learning, I'm usually tinkering around and I like having some project going on, even if it's only tweaking my Linux machine. Outside of work, I enjoy fixing stuff around the house and I love balancing on slacklines.

### **EXPERIENCE**

## Full stack developer

#### **Kasaz**

# July 2020 - present, Barcelona

Kasaz is a real state portal built with react and ruby on rails. We are operating fully remote. I have developed multiple features taking into consideration multiple devices, performance, software scalability and user experience. The most complex features I've built are:

- Search listings by drawing a hand-drawn area or panning the map automatically
- Feed generation to be ingested by traffic providers, involving complex queries that have to run for any amount of listings.
- Alert system to keep users up to date with new listings according to saved searches and other business logic

# Entrepreneur in residence

#### Zinc.vc

Sept 2019 - Feb 2020, London

Zinc is a startup incubator with a social focus.

- We explored two ideas in the telemedicine space, developed two prototypes using react and react-native.
- Built multiple relationships with different investors and advisors to start building a business from the ground up.
- Improved my negotiation skills and gained knowledge of how the startup world operates at a higher level.

# Software engineer

#### **DataTiger**

Oct 2017 - Nov 2018, London

At DataTiger we built a marketing tool, horizontally scalable following a microservices architecture using mainly Java and Python on Docker and AWS.

- I joined at a very early stage, being the 8th hire I developed, designed, and architected key features of the platform.
- I integrated our platform with different systems (email providers, other event providers, ad networks, among others).
- I developed the first parts of the analytics system based on a data lake architecture.
- Architected and developed fail resilient GDPR system, responsible for allowing users to request GDPR deletion of their data.

## Junior software engineer

#### King

Jun 2016 - Sep 2017, Barcelona

I joined as an intern during summer 2016, then got hired as a full-time backend developer. We developed a marketing internal system built on Jboss, AWS Redshift and Kafka, using Agile methodologies.

- I implemented end to end rich media notifications across all King games.
- I developed multiple backend features that incorporated into an ETL process.

## **PROJECTS**

When I have some time and mental bandwidth, I like building software as well. My main projects are:

Mac Remote, an android app I did a while ago, got a fair amount of downloads. Currently unmaintained. Agustibau.com, my personal portfolio, I'm trying to make it beautiful and somewhat usable.

My linux machine, I really like tinkering with my machine as it feels like sharpening my chisels.

# **EDUCATION**

## Bachelor's degree in computer science

Barcelona School of Informatics • Barcelona • 2018 • 7.3 (out of 10)